<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming | dvshilonosov</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/programming/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Programming</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/programming/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website creation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to make a website yourself: all the ways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want to develop a website, today you can choose any of 3 options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; write a project from scratch in HTML, CSS and Javascript;

 collect it on the website builder;

 run through the CMS system.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option for creating websites is the most time-consuming of all. To tell from and to about all the stages and processes in it, even one long article is not enough. Therefore, we will talk about this method next time. But if the easy way isn&amp;rsquo;t for you, start learning these languages with the Skysmart website building course. There we will talk about the features of each of them, teach you how to code and introduce you to the basics of web design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this article we will analyze the last two methods: website builders and CMS systems.
What are CMS systems and how to create sites on them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s figure out what lies behind this abbreviation - CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CMS is a content management system; a special program with a wide range of functions that allows you to create, edit and manage content on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, CMS is a kind of engine for Internet resources, with which you can customize them. Now let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick look at a few popular CMS systems and compare them with each other.
WordPress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress is one of the most popular CMS platforms. It has many ready-made templates, and you can also create a blog, business card site and other projects based on this platform for free. And all this - without knowing the code! The best thing is to make your first website on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you also set up plugins and add to this the skills of working with the PHP programming language, you can increase the capabilities of Wordpress beyond its basic ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits of WordPress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why this CMS is so popular, let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of its advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; You can create a website on the platform for free. You only pay for the domain name and hosting. Moreover, both can also be found in the free version due to trial periods, etc.

 Just install the program. You can set up WordPress for work in a few clicks.

 Auto update. When a newer version of the CMS is released, it will be installed automatically.

 Intuitive work. WordPress has a clear interface: one glance at the button is enough to understand what it is for.

 Lots of templates. On the platform, you can find a bunch of ready-made solutions for sites of various formats: online blogs, information resources, etc. This makes it easy for a beginner to create sites on WordPress.

 The platform automatically adapts the site for different devices. This allows your projects to remain relevant to people who visit them from smartphones, PCs, laptops and tablets.

 &amp;quot;Living&amp;quot; community. If you have any problems while working on the site, you can always find the answer to any question on the forum. And if it didn’t work out, just ask it and you will definitely be answered.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages of WordPress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As good as this platform is, it also has its downsides. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a few of them. This will help avoid unpleasant surprises if you ever want to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Many plugins are made by third party developers. This means that they may not be compatible with official WordPress updates. And they also have errors that can “break” your design, and even viruses.

 Safety. WordPress is open source software. This means that it is easier for fraudsters to find weaknesses in it in order to use your project for their own purposes.

 No technical support from developers. If you run into a problem, you can not expect that you will write one letter and everything will be decided for you. On the other hand, we already wrote above about the developed WordPress community, which you can come to for advice.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We briefly talked about WordPress, but do not think that this is where our acquaintance with this CMS ended. In the second part of the article, we will return to it to understand how it works and how to create your first site on it from scratch.
opencart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenCart is a shareware CMS system popular in Russia. It is mainly suitable for the development of online stores. For example, in the Russian Federation, more than 30% of e-commerce projects have been assembled on the basis of this platform. Those who have already used OpenCart say that it is convenient to use and easy to install. And also that it is suitable for those who want to save money on creating a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits of OpenCart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why users like this platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Developed community. As with WordPress, OpenCart has many live forums where extensions, beginner guides, and new themes are posted. And there you can always ask for advice from more experienced users if you encounter a problem.

 Analytics system. It is built into OpenCart, but if its basic functions are not enough, you can expand them by connecting Google Analytics or Yandex.Metrica.

 Good set of basic features. You can set up product filters, connect the desired payment system, add a subscription function, and much more.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can manage multiple sites from one admin panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages of OpenCart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This CMS system is also not perfect. Here are a few cons that OpenCart users most often complain about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; If you install too many plugins, the platform can run slowly and slow down your sites.

 Not all extensions are safe. If you install third-party plugins, you run the risk of leaking data to intruders.

 To &amp;quot;make friends&amp;quot; your online store with SEO, you will have to find and download the right extension. Without it, it will be difficult to promote the site in the search.

 Sometimes new versions of OpenCart are incompatible with some website modules.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joomla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joomla is the second most popular CMS system, the functions of which make it universal in creating and managing websites. Unlike the same OpenCart, it is well suited for all categories of sites: from online stores to personal blogs. Mastering it is no more difficult than other CMS systems. But if you need a small site, it will be easier to work with the designers than with her. Joomla is chosen when they want to make a medium or large project. In them, she fully reveals her potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of Joomla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the advantages of Joomla, which, according to users, distinguish it from other CMS systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Lots of basic features. And their list can be expanded even more if you install the necessary plugins.

 The popularity of the platform among users. Those who often work with Joomla are constantly creating new useful content about it. For example, guides for beginners, life hacks and plugin collections.

 Joomla functionality is not designed to create one specific type of project. This means that it is equally convenient to work on this platform when creating different sites: business cards, online stores, landing pages, etc.

 Joomla developers often release fresh updates that fix version errors and add to the platform&#39;s feature set.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages of Joomla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget to tell about some points that you may not like in working with this platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Low level of security. Joomla site code is not so well protected. This means that it will be vulnerable to scammers who can take advantage of security holes.

 Sometimes, after updating the CMS, some plugins may stop working. This is due to the incompatibility of their versions. Same problem as WordPress.

 Despite the fact that Joomla is focused on large sites, they heavily load the server. Because of this, there are difficulties with access to the resource.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have briefly reviewed 3 popular CMS systems, we can compare them with each other. For convenience, we have done this in the table below, where we have collected all the main criteria. They will help you evaluate the platforms and understand which one is best for you to create a project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
